Finding Aid for William G. Milliken papers 1961-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Administrative / Executive Files
  - Staff Files, 224 linear feet
    - Peter Ellsworth/Ken Frankland 1969-1982
      - Topical Files
        - Joseph, John Anthony See Corrections (Box 683)
        - Judges
          - Coalition for Merit Selection of Judges (Petition Drive) 1978 (Box 683)
          - Retirement Fund (Goodwillie) 1976 (Box 683)
          - Retirement System (Box 683)
          - Slotting Bill (PA 134) 1977 (Box 683)
        - Judgeships (Box 683)
        - Judicial Appointments 1976-1977, 3 folders (Box 683)
        - Judicial Conduct (Proposed Code) (Box 683)
        - Judicial Manpower (Additional) (Box 683)
        - Judicial Revision Constitutional Amendment (Article 6) (Box 683)
        - Judicial Tenure Commission (Box 683)
        - Judicial Vacancy
          - Oakland County Circuit Court (Box 683)
          - St. Clair Circuit Court (Box 683)
        - Jury Commissioners (PA 326) 1968 (Box 683)
        - Jury Reform (One Day/One Trial) (Box 683)
        - Justice (Subcabinet) (Box 683)
        - Justice Cabinet Committee 1977 (Box 683)
        - Juvenile Code (HB 4573) 1972 (Box 683)
        - Juvenile Delinquency Prevention Program (Box 683)
        - Juvenile Justice (Box 683)
        - Juvenile Officers (County) (Box 683)
        - Juvenile Waivers 1972 (Box 683)
        - Kalamazoo School Board See Recall (Box 683)
        - Kalbfleish, Ina See Burnside Township (Box 683)
        - Kanoyton, Silverenia See Licensing and Regulation, Ethics (Box 683)
        - Karoub, James (Interview w. Gordon) 1976 (Box 683)
        - Kaufman, Charles See Removal Requests (Box 683)
        - Kellogg Company (Anti-Trust) (Box 683)
        - Kennedy, Jane (Box 683)
        - Kent County Legal Aid and Defender Association (Box 683)
        - Kimball, Paul See Sheriffs' Department (Box 683)
        - King, Martin Luther (Holiday) (Box 683)
        - Kirtland Community College (Roscommon) (Box 683)
        - Klimczuk vs. General Motors Corporation et al (Workers Compensation Appeal Board) (Box 683)
        - Koscot Interplanetary, Inc (Box 683)
        - Kratchman vs. City of Detroit See Detroit (Box 683)
        - Labor, 2 folders (Box 683)
          (See also Civil Service: Hospitals: State Employer, Office of)
        - Labor Arbitrations (Box 683)
        - Labor Party (United States) (Box 683)
        - Labor Subcabinet (Box 683)
        - Lake Carriers' Association vs. McMullan et al (Box 683)
        - Lakey Foundry (Box 684)
        - Lance, Paul A. See Removal Requests (Box 684)
        - Land Sales Act (HB 5273) (Box 684)
        - Land Use Legislation (Box 684)
        - Lansing City Councilmen (Nosal) (Box 684)
        - Lansing School Board See Recall (Box 684)
        - Lapeer State Home and Training School See Mental Health (Box 684)
        - Law, Robert (Appointment) (Box 684)
        - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration (Box 684)
        - Law Enforcement Officers (SB 613) 1965 (Box 684)
        - Law Library, State 1979 (Box 684)
        - Law Revision Commission (Box 684)
        - Law Suits (Box 684)
        - Leelanau County Board of Commissioner vs. State of Michigan and Department of Natural Resources (Box 684)
        - Legal Aid (Box 684)
        - Legal Appointments See Appointments (Box 684)
        - Legal Assistant (Box 684)
        - Legal Briefs
          - Milliken vs. Green 1972, 4 folders (Box 684)
          - San Antonio Independent School District vs. Rodriguez, 1971-2 (Box 684)
          - Michigan Litigation Pertaining to Education, 1972-75 (Box 684)
        - Legal Services (Box 684)
        - Legislation
          - General, 2 folders (Box 684)
          - 1974 (Box 684)
          - House Joint Resolutions, 3 folders (Box 684)
          - Line Item Vetoes August 1977 (Box 685)
          - Merit Shop Contracting (HB4233) 1978 (Box 685)
          - Moped (Box 685)
          - Peremptory Challenge of Judges (Veto, HB 3835) (Box 685)
          - Political Reform Package (Fall Agenda) 1976 (Box 685)
          - Public Employees Right to Strike, 2 folders (Box 685)
          - Rule-Making (SB 1064), 2 folders (Box 685)
          - Sunset 1982 (Box 685)
          - Tax Shift Proposal (SJR-X) 1980 (Box 685)
          - Telephone Monitoring (H 4372) 1978 (Box 685)
          - Traffic Offenses, Decriminalization of 1978 (Box 685)
          - See also Popular Name of Legislation (Box 685)
        - Legislative Apportionment See also Apportionment and Reapportionment (Box 685)
        - Legislative Status Reports See Executive Orders and Directives (Box 685)
        - Licenses, Occupational (Consideration of Prior Convictions) (Box 685)
        - Licensing and Regulation, Department of
          - General (Box 685)
          - Ballenger III, William S (Box 685)
          - Banks, Mr (Box 685)
          - Board of Accountancy (Box 685)
          - Board of Registration for Professional Community Planners (Box 685)
          - Kanoyton, Silverenia (Box 685)
          - Mobile Homes, 2 folders (Box 685)
          - Organizational Problems (Box 686)
          - Owens Committee (Box 686)
          - Professional and Occupational, 2 folders (Box 686)
          - Proposed Legislation (Box 686)
        - Line Item Vetoes See also Legislation (Box 686)
        - Liquor Control Commission, 5 folders (Box 686)
        - Livonia Board of Education (Box 686)
        - Lobby Reform, 3 folders (Box 686)
          See also Elections, Ethics, Fair Campaign Practices Commission
        - Lobbyists and Lobbying, 3 folders (Box 686)
        - Lobodocky, Andrew See Removal Requests (Box 686)
        - Long, Bill (Box 686)
        - Lottery
          - General, 2 folders (Box 686)
          - Appointment of Commissioner 1979 (Box 686)
          - Computer 1980 (Box 686)
          - Jar Game Legislation (Box 686)
        - Lt. Governor
          - Brickley (Citizens for an Improved Ballot) (Box 686)
          - Damman (Box 686)
          - Retirement 1979 (Box 686)
        - Mackinac Bridge, 3 folders (Box 687)
        - Mackinac Bridge Authority, 2 folders (Box 687)
        - McLogan, Matt (Public Service Commission) (Box 687)
        - McMullan, Ralph See Lake Carriers' Association (Box 687)
        - Malpractice (Box 687)
        - Management and Budget, Department of (Box 687)
        - Management Group (Box 687)
        - Management Sciences Group (Executive Office) (Box 687)
        - Manistique Labor Dispute (Box 687)
        - Marijuana (Therapeutic Use) (Box 687)
        - Mead Corporation (Box 687)
        - Medicaid See also Social Services (Box 687)
        - Medical Practices Board (Box 687)
        - Medical Technicians, Emergency (Box 687)
        - Meharg, Norman D. See Removal Requests (Box 687)
        - Mental Health
          - General (Box 687)
          - Advisory Council (Box 687)
          - Caro Hospital Problem (Box 687)
          - Civil Commitment Problems (Box 687)
          - Deinstitutionalization, 3 folders (Box 687)
          - Employee Protection (Box 687)
          - Facility Construction and Planning Authority (Box 687)
          - Lapeer State Home and Training Center (Box 687)
          - Litigation (Box 687)
          - Martin, Dr. (Clinton Valley Removal Request) (Box 687)
          - Northeast Michigan Community Mental Health (Box 687)
          - Northville Psychiatric Hospital 1979 (Box 687)
          - Oakdale Regional Center (Box 687)
          - Plymouth Center 1978 (Box 687)
          - Quit Claims Deeds (Box 688)
          - Smith, Donald (Investigation) (Box 688)
          - Statute Review Commission (Box 688)
          - See also Decker vs. Michigan Nursing Care Facilities (Box 688)
        - Mental Patients (Constitutional Rights/Judge Gilmore's Decision/State vs. Bargy (Box 688)
        - Mercury Contamination See Wyandotte Chemical Corporation (Box 688)
        - Merit Shop Contracting See Legislation (Box 688)
        - Michigan Association of Chiefs of Police See State Police (Box 688)
        - Michigan Association of Counties, 2 folders (Box 688)
        - Michigan Efficiency Task Force, 2 folders (Box 688)
        - Michigan Employment Relations Commission (Box 688)
        - Michigan Employment Securities Act (MESA) (Amendments to) 1977 (Box 688)
        - Michigan Employment Securities Commission
          - General (Box 688)
          - Appeal Board, 2 folders (Box 688)
          - Lawsuit 1979 (Box 688)
          - Office Security (Box 688)
          - See also Removal Requests and Investigations, State Employer (Box 688)
        - Michigan Environmental Review Board
          - General, 3 folders (Box 688)
          - Environmental Review Statement (Box 688)
        - Michigan Equal Employment Opportunity Council
          - General (Box 689)
          - 1975-77, 3 folders (Box 689)
        - Michigan Job Development Authority See Volkswagen (Box 689)
        - Michigan National Bank Dispute (Box 689)
        - Michigan Senatorial Trust (Box 689)
        - Michigan Technological University (Disclosure Information) 1976 (Box 689)
        - Michigan Youth Services Information Systems, 3 folders (Box 689)
        - Military Affairs, Department of
          - General, 2 folders (Box 689)
          - Budget, 1978-79 see Budget (Box 689)
          - Sager, Wendell 1978 (Box 689)
          - Selfridge Air Force Base, 2 folders (Box 689)
          - Vietnam Bonus 1976 (Box 689)
        - Military Board (Box 689)
        - Milliken for Michigan Committee vs. Joint Council 43, Teamsters October 15, 1979 (Box 689)
        - Milliken 388 Committee See Campaign Finance (Box 689)
        - Missing Persons (Box 689)
        - Mobile Homes See also Licensing and Regulation (Box 689)
        - Moiles, Victor E. See Removal Requests (Box 689)
        - Monroe, Loren See Corrections (Box 689)
        - Moped See Legislation (Box 689)
        - Mortgages, Second (Box 689)
        - Mortuary Science Board (Box 689)
        - Motor Vehicle Repair Facilities Act (Emergency Rules, Court Orders) 1977 (Box 689)
        - Mt. Clemens Tunnel Explosion (Box 689)
        - Myomassologists 1977 (Box 689)
        - Nadolney, Gerome See Removal Requests (Box 690)
        - Nara, Dr (Box 690)
        - Narcotics Ass Substance Abuse, Controlled Substances (Box 690)
        - National Coalition Against Death Penalty See Capital Punishment (Box 690)
        - National Guard
          - General (Box 690)
          - Appointments (Miscellaneous) (Box 690)
          - Double Pay (Box 690)
          - Fires (Grayling) (Box 690)
          - Officer Promotions (Box 690)
          - Okhuysen Case (Box 690)
          - Personnel Inquiry and General Matters (Box 690)
        - National Organizations for Women vs. Idaho (Box 690)
        - Native Americans
          - Commission on Indian Affairs, 2 folders (Box 690)
          - Fishing Rights, 4 folders (Box 690)
          - Land Trust (Box 690)
        - Natural Resources, Department of
          - General, 2 folders (Box 691)
          - Air Quality Control (Grosse Pointe-Clinton Refuse Disposal Authority) 1980 (Box 691)
          - Clear Water Bond (Box 691)
          - Conflict of Interest (Box 691)
          - Forest Improvement Districts (Box 691)
          - Legal (Box 691)
          - Reorganization 1976, 2 folders (Box 691)
          - State Flood Insurance 1978 (Box 691)
        - Ninth District Court Appointments See Appointments (Box 691)
        - No Fault Insurance, 2 folders (Box 691)
        - Noise Pollution (Box 691)
        - Northern Michigan Growth Conference See Upper Great Lakes Regional Commission (Box 691)
        - Northern Michigan University See Campus Disorders (Box 691)
        - Northville Psychiatric Hospital See Mental Health (Box 691)
        - Notary Public, 2 folders (Box 691)
        - Nuclear Civil Protection 1979 (Box 691)
        - Nuclear Emergency Preparedness Plan See also Atomic Energy, Civil Emergencies, Emergency Procedures, Executive Orders (Box 691)
        - Nuclear Regulatory Commission (Box 691)
        - Nuclear Shipments 1981 (Box 691)
        - Nuclear Wastes (Box 691)
        - Nursing Associations See Hospitals (Box 691)
        - Nursing Care Facilities See Mental Health (Box 691)
        - Nutrition, Office of (Box 691)
        - Oakdale Regional Center See Mental Health (Box 691)
        - Oakland County
          - Circuit Court See Judicial Vacancy (Box 691)
          - Gas and Weight Tax Proposal (Box 691)
          - Road Commission vs. State Highway Commission (Box 691)
        - O'Brien, Allen (Box 691)
        - Obscenity Legislation
          - General (Box 691)
          - HB 5003, 1973 (Box 691)
        - Occupational Health Standards Commission (Box 691)
        - Occupational Information Coordinating Committee May 15, 1978 (Box 691)
        - Okhuysen Case See National Guard (Box 691)
        - Ombudsman (Box 691)
        - One Day/One Trial See Jury Reform (Box 691)
        - Open Meetings, 4 folders (Box 692)
        - Operation C.A.R.E. See State Police (Box 692)
        - Optometry Board (Box 692)
        - Optometry, School of (Box 692)
        - O'Rourke, Peter See Michigan Employment Securities Commission Appeal Board (Box 692)
        - Osteopathic Medicine, Advisory Board (Box 692)
        - Owendale-Gagetown Area School District (Municipal Finance Commission) (Box 692)
        - Owens Committee See Licensing and Regulation (Box 692)
        - Package Liquor Legislation 1970 (Box 692)
        - Pappas, Louis A. See Removal Requests (Box 692)
        - Pardons and Commutions (Box 692)
        - Pardons and Recommendations (Box 692)
        - Parens Patriae Lawsuit Bill (HR 8532) 1976 (Box 692)
        - Parole Board
          - 1979 (Box 692)
          - Bill (Box 692)
          - Good Time Issue (Box 692)
          - See also Corrections, Criminal Justice (Box 692)
        - Parsons, Betty See Taxpayers and Citizens in the Public Interest (Box 692)
        - Patino, Patric A. See Elections (Box 692)
        - Patrols See Sheriffs' Department, State Police (Box 692)
        - Patterson, Brooks See Removal Requests (Box 692)
        - PBB, 1975-80, 5 folders (Box 693)
        - PCB (Box 693)
        - Penn, Robert See Removal Requests (Box 693)
        - Pentwater River Game Area See Red Barn Area (Box 693)
        - Personnel See Civil Service, State Employer (Box 693)
        - Pharmacy Board (Box 693)
        - Phillips, Frank See Removal Requests (Box 693)
        - Physicians' Assistants (Box 693)
        - Physicians' Compensation (Box 693)
        - Pigeon River (Oil Drilling) (Box 693)
        - Platte River Hatchery (Box 693)
        - Plymouth Center See Mental Health (Box 693)
        - Plymouth Township Boundary Commission (Box 693)
        - Podiatry Board (Box 693)
        - Political Reform
          - General, 3 folders (Box 693)
          - Act 1975 (Box 693)
          - Revisions 1977 (Box 693)
          - Republican Package (Box 693)
        - Polygraph Examiners Board, Forensic 1978 (Box 694)
        - Polygraph Legislation (SB 478) 1972 (Box 694)
        - Pontiac Stadium (Box 694)
        - Pornography (Box 694)
        - Port Huron Tunnel Explosion, 2 folders (Box 694)
        - Powelson, Donald R. See Removal Requests (Box 694)
        - Presidential Preference Primary See Elections (Box 694)
        - Press Access to Medical Lists See Social Services (Box 694)
        - Prison Disturbances, See Corrections (Box 694)
        - Prisoner's Labor Union (Charles Thompson) (Box 694)
        - Prisoners Progress Association (Claude Williams, Jackson Prison) (Box 694)
        - Prisons See Corrections (Box 694)
        - Prisons and Corrections, Committee on (Box 694)
        - Probate Court (Box 694)
        - Probate Judges, 2 folders (Box 694)
        - Probate Stenographers (Court Reporters) (Box 694)
        - Professional Community Planners, Board of Registration for See Licensing and Regulations (Box 694)
        - Professional Service Contractors (Box 694)
        - Program Council (Box 694)
        - Project Seafarer (ELF) 1977 (Box 694)
        - Privacy (Box 694)
        - Proposal C (Constitutional Amendment) 1972, 3 folders (Box 694)
        - Public Employees, Commission for Distinguished (Box 694)
        - Public Employees Right to Strike See Legislation (Box 694)
        - Public Health Service Hospital See United States (Box 694)
        - Public Health Statute Review Commission (Box 694)
        - Public Intoxication (Box 694)
        - Public Safety Award (President's) See State Police (Box 694)
        - Public Service Commission
          - Appointment (Box 694)
          - Complaints (Box 694)
          - Rate Cases (Box 694)
          - See also Matt McLogan (Box 694)
        - Public Utilities Securities Issue 1981 (Box 694)
        - Quit Claims Deeds See Mental Health (Box 694)
        - Racing See also Hazel Park Racing Association, Jackson Raceway (Box 695)
        - Racing Commissioner See also Appointments (Box 695)
        - Raffle Bill (HB 4862) 1975 (Box 695)
        - Raffles, Lotteries, Games of Chance (Box 695)
        - Railroad Policemen (Box 695)
        - Railroads
          - General (Box 695)
          - Derailments (Newaygo County), 1979-80 (Box 695)
          - Lake Superior and Ishpeming (Box 695)
          - Penn Central 1977 (Box 695)
        - Reagan, Ronald (Campaign) (Box 695)
        - Real Estate License Law Study Commission (Box 695)
        - Reapportionment See Apportionment and Reapportionment (Box 695)
        - Recall
          - General (Box 695)
          - Belding (Box 695)
          - Benton Harbor (Box 695)
          - Benzie County (Almira Township) (Box 695)
          - Caledonia Township (Box 695)
          - China Township (Box 695)
          - Hamtramck (Box 695)
          - Hillsdale County (Jefferson Township) 1980 (Box 695)
          - Kalamazoo School Board 1978 (Box 695)
          - Keego Harbor 1971 (Box 695)
          - Lansing School Board (Box 695)
          - Macomb County (Lenox Township) 1980 (Box 695)
          - Madison Heights 1976 (Box 695)
          - Marine City (Box 695)
          - New Buffalo (Box 695)
          - Orchard Lake (Box 695)
          - Portland (Box 695)
          - Romulus (Box 695)
          - Royal Oak Township (Box 695)
          - Sandusky City Council August, 1979 (Box 695)
          - Sterling Heights (Box 695)
          - Wyoming City Council (Box 695)
        - Recorder's Court
          - General (Box 695)
          - Jury Commissioners (Box 695)
        - Recreation Bonding Program (Box 695)
        - Red Barn Area (Pentwater River State Game Area) 1976 (Box 695)
        - Referendum Requests 1976, 1978 (Box 695)
        - Region 2 Law Enforcement Planning Council See Urban Cooperation Act (Box 695)
        - Regulatory Review Task Force (Box 695)
        - Regulatory Subcabinet (Box 695)
        - Removal Requests and Investigations
          - General (Public Officials by Governor) (Box 695)
          - Attorneys
            - Gerome Nadolney (Gogebic County) (Box 695)
            - Brooks Patterson (Oakland County) (Box 695)
            - Walter Turton (St. Clair County) (Box 695)
          - Sheriffs
            - Roger Dean (Calhoun County) 1978 (Box 695)
            - Lonnie G. Deur (Lake County) 1979 (Box 695)
            - Eugene Hoag (Eaton County) (Box 695)
            - Jenema (Missaukee County) (Box 695)
            - Paul A. Lance (Wexford County) (Box 695)
            - Norman D. Meharg (St. Clair County) (Box 695)
            - Victor Moiles (Shiawassee County) 1978 (Box 695)
            - Donald R. Powelson (Ontonagon County) (Box 695)
            - Edward O. Webb (Hillsdale County) 1976 (Box 695)
            - Robert J. Whitcomb (Allegan County) (Box 695)
        - Removal Requests and Investigations
          - Other
            - Marion Chalfant (Leoni Township Clerk, Jackson County) (Box 695)
            - Ross K. Childs (Washtenaw County) (Box 695)
            - George Crockett (Judge) (Box 695)
            - William Eldridge (Cemetery Commission) 1980 (Box 695)
            - Flint Township Tax Commissioner 1974 (Box 695)
            - Forrest (Nick) Jewel (Berrien County) (Box 695)
            - Charles Kaufman (Judge) (Box 695)
            - Andrew Lobodocky (West Bloomfield Township Treasurer) (Box 696)
            - Robert Penn (MESC) (Box 696)
            - Frank Phillips (Grand Haven Township) (Box 696)
            - Dorothy Staley (Delta County Clerk) (Box 696)
            - Frank Szymanski (Judge); Senator Charles N. Youngblood and Louis A. Pappas (Wayne County Grand Jury Indictment), 2 folders (Box 696)
            - See also Friend of the Court, Huron Township, Mental Health/Dr. Morton (Box 696)
        - Rent Freeze Cases (Landlord-Tenant) (Box 696)
        - Reorganization Research See Executive Orders (Box 696)
        - Republican Party
          - Governor's Association 1972 (Box 696)
          - National Convention 1980 (Box 696)
          - Organization (Box 696)
          - Political Candidates 1978 (Box 696)
        - Reserve Mining Company (Box 696)
        - Rhoads, Douglas C. See Huron Township (Box 696)
        - Riots See Corrections, Emergency Procedures (Box 696)
        - River Rouge (Request for Emergency Powers) (Box 696)
        - Robey, Ames vs. Dr. Donald C. Smith, 1975-76 (Box 696)
        - Rock Festivals (State Fairgrounds) 1971 See also State Fair Authority (Box 696)
        - Rome, Lou (Box 696)
        - Rose, Jack (Box 696)
        - Royal Oak Township (Grand Jury Investigation) (Box 696)
        - Rutherford, James See Students for a Democratic Society (Box 696)
        - Sabena (Belgian World Airlines vs. Western Union) (Box 696)
        - Safety Commission (State) (Box 696)
        - Sager, Wendell See Military Affairs (Box 696)
        - Saginaw vs. State of Michigan, 1981-82 (Box 696)
        - St. Augustine Seminary See FOIA (Box 696)
        - St. Clair Circuit Court See Judicial Vacancy (Box 696)
        - School Millage (HR WWW) 1970 (Box 696)
        - Schultz, Martin See Conflict of Interest (Box 696)
        - Schwade, Louis See Corrections (Box 696)
        - Science and Technology, Office of (Within Executive Office) 1978 (Box 696)
        - Seafarer See Project Seafarer (Box 696)
        - Seat Belts, Mandatory (Box 696)
        - Selective Service, 2 folders (Box 696)
        - Selfridge Air Force Base See Military Affairs (Box 696)
        - Senate Confirmation of Governor's Appointments See also Appointments (Box 696)
        - Sentencing Structures (Judicial) (Box 696)
        - Shell Oil (Kalkaska Labor Dispute) (Box 696)
        - Sheriffs' Associates (Charles White) (Box 696)
        - Sheriffs' Departments
          - Genesse County (Paul Kimball) (Box 696)
          - Luce County (Michigan State Police Problems) 1979 (Box 696)
          - Patrols (SB 1682 SB 1517) (Box 696)
        - Shiawassee Drain Commission 1979 (Box 696)
        - Shield Law (HB 4476) 1973 (Box 696)
        - Sick Leave, Accrued (Unclassified Employees) (Box 696)
        - Silverdome 1981 (Box 696)
        - Sinclair, John (Box 696)
        - Slotting Bill See Judges (Box 696)
        - Small Business
          - General (Box 697)
          - Advisory Council (Box 697)
          - Executive Directive 1976 (Box 697)
          - Minority Business (Box 697)
        - Smith, Donald (Investigation) See Mental Health (Box 697)
        - Social Services
          - Appropriations (Box 697)
          - Battise, William P. 1979 See Administrative Hearing (Box 697)
          - Brown, Charles (Box 697)
          - Halverson, George (Box 697)
          - Ingham County Welfare Fund (Box 697)
          - Legal (Box 697)
          - Office of Children and Youth Services 1978 (Box 697)